Abdo Ez Aldeen

85A Smithdown Lane Liverpool L7 3EE \$\infty\$07426 000 286 abdo.ezaldeen@hotmail.com

Personal Profile

I have recently completed a master's in Advanced Mechanical Engineering, also I hold a CSCS card. A reliable, self-motivated and enthusiastic individual who can take on the coordinating duties of supervisory and maintenance roles, as well as, designing and developing projects. Possessing extensive experience of supporting, developing and motivating teams to do better and drive continuous improvements across a range of work activities.

Education & Training

The University of Liverpool

2017 - 2018

MSc in Advanced Mechanical Engineering

Modules studied: (Advanced Manufacturing With Lasers, Additive Manufacturing, Engineering Fluid, Energy and the Environment, Enterprise Studies, IC Engine, Mechatronics, Research Skills and Project Planning, Structural Integrity)

Damascus University, Syria

1998 - 2006

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering

HITEC Power Protection (Turkish): Training on how to run a UPS electrical generator **Nestle Dubai:** Training workshop of ETS (Energy Target Setting) to optimize the energy consumption at KIKAT factory in Dubai

Nestle Syria: Training workshop of Getting Start as New Leader

Employment History

A&B Engineering, Liverpool, UK

2019 - 2019

Trainee Design Engineer (Training course for 3 months)

Duties:

 Produce 2D drawings, 3D models and other documentation. Manage drawing change requests, and provide assistance to the construction Engineering team.

Al Badia Cement, Adra, Syria Production Engineer Duties:

2015 - 2016

- Leading the manufacturing process of mining by grinding raw materials that include limestone and clay, to a fine powder, called raw meal
- Grinding a blend of cement clinker along with carefully selected supplementary cementitious materials
- Processing all raw materials including clinkers by a vertical roller mill or ball mill
- Putting milled raw materials go through a quality control process before being used in blends to produce the finished product
- Storing blends in finished product silos ensuring final inspection and testing is carried out before being dispatched

Nestle, Damascus, Syria Industrial Services & Workshop Engineer Duties:

2010 - 2013

 Leading and supervising technicians and achieving energy saving and ensuring that all utilities (steam, compressed air, nitrogen generation, cooling towers, child water, AHU, electricity, water, WWTP) needed for the factory are fulfilled and the energy/water consumption at the factory is working at optimum level

 Motivating team to apply TPM methodology by facilitating the methods, training, coaching, and auditing

Group Bel, Damascus, Syria Production Supervisor Duties:

2009 - 2010

• Controlling the manufacturing process and leading the workers arranging the working environment in order to achieve the production plan

National Petroleum Services, Al Hasakah, Syria Drilling (Operations & Logistics) Coordinator

2007- 2009

Duties:

- Following the drilling activities, completion and drilling equipment using land rig and drilling tools
- Liaising with customs and clearing agents to clear three brand-new land rigs forwarded from China shipments
- Co-ordinating between the rigs to provide them with all needs regarding the co-ordination of materials, inspections and services mobilisation through work site installation, post-job reporting and invoicing and the coordination between the venders and subcontracts companies and NPS company
- Carrying out on the job training about the well services activities (stimulation and nitrogen operations) and equipment (CT & pumps & bottom hole assembly)

Voluntary Work

British Red Cross, Liverpool, UK Refugee Case Worker

2016 - 2017

Duties:

- Providing one to one support to beneficiaries
- Undertaking sensitive and comprehensive interviews with service users to assess their needs and agreeing a plan of action with the beneficiary

IT Skills

- MS Office (Excel Advanced)
- AutoCAD (2D 3D)
- Mechanical Desktop 6
- (SAP) Implementation
- Pro Engineer Software & PTC Creo

Key skills

- Excellent concentration levels whilst performing repetitive tasks
- Ability to manage the work and execute the actions plan
- Ability to use initiative using excellent problem solving skills
- Effectively communicates, supports and motivates team members
- Fully committed to delivering a high quality service in every aspect of work

References Available on Request